BRIAN D. KIDD

(206) 683-7451 briankiddmedia.com brian.kidd.one@gmail.com github.com/briankidd9design

SUMMARY

Web Developer/Designer and UX Designer specializing in UI/Front End Development and UX Design. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects including Full Stack JavaScript and PHP. Extensive application of programming languages HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, PHP. Experience with creating wireframes, mockups, and prototypes in Sketch, Adobe XD, Figma, and Balsamiq. Strong background in design, UX research, communications, and application testing.

SKILLS

Advanced	Intermediate	Proficient
HTML5	Adobe XD	Drupal
CSS3	Sketch	WordPress
JavaScript	Figma	ASP.NET
jQuery	InVision	LAMP
Bootstrap	MEAN/MERN	Photoshop
Express.js	Node.js	Illustrator
UX Design	React	
	PHP	

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front End Developer

02/2020 - 04/2020 Laid off due to COVID-19

The Boeing Company via PDS Tech, Inc, Tukwila WA

- Program websites for Boeing and its affiliates and subsidiaries
- Provide web maintenance and support of multiple external and internal Boeing websites
- Build new pages and sites as part of large sales projects
- Work in a variety of different environments, from hand-coded HTML/CSS sites to an enterprise-level CMS
- Participate in the planning, development, and launch of new builds
 Tech: TeamSite CMS, HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, Angular, JavaScript, WordPress

Web Developer/Webmaster (part-time)

2019 - 2020

Laid off due to COVID-19

Online Developer Plus, Inc./ondevplus.com, Kirkland, WA

- Work directly with the founder and CEO to help launch the company by building its website using HTML5, CSS3, and jQuery
- Design and develop company's website as well as make updates upon requests such as code, copy, images, graphic design, and layout

- Built website using the Bootstrap framework for responsive design on all devices
- Customized CSS, including creating media queries for responsive design

Personal Assistant/Family Hardship

2016 - 2019

- My dad unexpectedly passed away in March 2016 and mom was recovering from breast cancer at the time
- Helped mom adjust and transition to adopting responsibilities that were formerly my dad's for 40-plus years
- Helped with financial adjustments including budgeting, taxes, paying bills, and selling
- Mom is now healthier, adjusted, and more independent
- During this time, I furthered my education by completing Free Code Camp's Front End Development Program and earning Treehouse's Full Stack JavaScript Techdegree along with earning a Web Application Programming Degree from an accredited college

Partner, Co-Founder and Multimedia Developer (side hustle)

2014 - Present

ExoMedia Productions (formerly Kylmyys Media), Kenmore, WA

- Develop and maintain websites for businesses using an array of frameworks and Content Management Systems. Languages used include HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and PHP
- Execute branding for businesses including logo design and developing or refining mission statements
- Compose and edit website content for clients
- Produce and license music for documentaries and film
- Perform music for clients including Chophouse Row and Axis Pioneer Square

Tutor for Web Applications Programming

2015 - 2016

Cascadia College, Bothell, WA

- Assisted students in subjects covered in the Web Applications Programming Technology program (For details use URL: http://goo.gl/C1vW3B)
- Provided tutoring in HTML, CSS3, Java, JavaScript, C#, MySql, Photoshop, and Illustrator
- Offered guidance about using different IDEs in Linux, Mac OS, and Windows operating
- Developed approaches to help students understand complex programming concepts

Corporate Communications Specialist

2014 - 2015

Federal Home Loan Bank of Seattle, Seattle, WA

- Assisted webmaster with design and web content editing
- Composed and edited internal bank news publication
- Assisted the Director of Corporate Relations with the bank's complicated merger
- Researched and assisted in the creation of the bank's Social Media Policy
- Composed press releases, web content, and marketing materials

Financial Operations Specialist

2012 - 2013

Solavei via Aerotek, Bellevue, WA (Telecommunications startup)

- Assisted in Finance and Customer Care to help facilitate the launch of a startup company
- Served as a communications liaison between Customer Care and the Finance

Department to increase billing efficiency

• Handled complex account adjustments to ensure reporting accuracy

Data Analyst 2010 - 2012

Google via Aerotek, Kirkland/Bothell, WA

- Meticulously reviewed and edited user data entered into innovative mapping programs
- Helped orchestrate internal and external policies related to Google Maps to ensure user online map accuracy
- Collaborated with eight other project teams to coordinate the world-wide distribution and services associated with Google Maps
- Managed the international influx feed of data for Google Maps
- Edited text format of electronic reader

CERTIFICATIONS

UX Design Techdegree

July 2019

Treehouse, Portland, OR (teamtreehouse.com)

- Learned research methods and practices of UX Design
- Created wireframes, mockups and prototypes

Full Stack JavaScript Techdegree

Sept 2019

Treehouse, Portland, OR (teamtreehouse.com)

- Learned to create Full Stack JavaScript web applications
 - JavaScript, Node, React, Express, SQL

Front End Development Program Certificate

April 2017

Free Code Camp, San Francisco, CA (freecodecamp.org)

- Learned the intricacies of Front End Development
- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery

EDUCATION

Associate in Applied Science: Web Application Programming Technology <u>Cascadia College, Bothell, WA</u> June 2016

- Learned how to build Web Applications
- Languages covered included HTML, JavaScript, Java, C#, MySql, PHP, and ASP.NET.
- Strong emphasis on Responsive Design
- Awarded both President's and Faculty Honors for high scholastic achievement

Bachelor of Arts: Journalism

June 2003

University of Washington, Seattle, WA

- Earned Excellence in Journalism Award from the UW Department of Communication
- Dean's List